Peter Musembi Wambua

Resolute, Goal-oriented cybersecurity individual experienced in ethical hacking, penetration testing, vulnerability analysis, network security, and security operations. Energetic, teachable, and technical-minded individual. I possess exceptional skills in scripting with Python and C, Red Team toolkits such as Metasploit and Burp Suite, and SOC tools like SIEM, EDR, and SOAR tools.

Nairobi, Kenya **Phone:** +254714873020

Mail: peterwambua025@gmail.com
GitHub: github.com/wambuapeter
Socials: LinkedIn Twitter

Portfolio: https://wambuapeter.github.io/

Blogs: Personal Blog Medium

EXPERIENCE

Cyb3rk1math1 — CTF Player

July 2022 - PRESENT

- Contributed to CTFs with this award-winning team leading to a consistent top 4 placement in all CTF competitions participated in, showcasing expertise and teamwork skills in cybersecurity challenges.
- Specialized in penetration testing challenges, including web, Android, and boot2root, leading to a 90% success rate in solving challenges within these categories.
- Collaborated with team members to develop innovative solutions to problems, resulting in the successful completion of over 100 challenges across various categories, demonstrating teamwork and problem-solving skills.

Hackerbro Technologies, Remote — Red Team Engineer intern

July 2023 - October 2023

- Conducted penetration testing simulations on over 15 systems, identifying and exploiting multiple vulnerabilities, thereby enhancing the organizations' cybersecurity resilience.
- Specialized in application security assessments, successfully identifying and remediating high-risk vulnerabilities in critical applications, reducing the organization's exposure to potential cyber threats.
- Generated comprehensive reports on penetration testing activities, highlighting over 10 key findings and recommendations, leading to over 20% improvement in the organization's overall security posture.

EDUCATION

Dedan Kimathi University of Technology — BSC in Computer Science(Reference)

August 2020 - May 2024

- Did well in my degree achieving a second upper division
- Demonstrated leadership by founding the Cyber Security Club of Kimathi and leading technical sessions. An active member of the Google Developers Students Club.

ALX Africa Holberton School, — Software Engineering certificate

June 2021 - May 2022

- Learned Linux basics, C, Python, Git, and project collaboration.
- Learned web development using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript then manipulated the back-end with Python.

PROJECTS

Static Testing Django Application — https://github.com/Wambuapeter/mobileWatchDog

• A static testing application for mobile APKs that I built on the Django framework and is pattern-based.

Django Password Manager — https://github.com/Wambuapeter/BadPass

• A secure password manager implemented using Django and using the best security features

Undergraduates API — https://github.com/Wambuapeter/undergradAPI

• This is a flask API to provide undergraduates with mentorship and sponsorship programs

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Penetration Testing and Vulnerability Assessment
- Security Operations and Forensics
- Active Directory and Wireless Penetration Testing
- Networking, Linux, Python Scripting
- API and Web Development, and Security

HUMAN SKILLS

- Project Management
- Communication Skills and Public Speaking
- Problem-solving, Leadership

CERTIFICATIONS

- Practical Ethical Hacking(PEH) <u>Link</u>
- Threat Hunting certification by VTFoundation <u>Link</u>
- SOC member by letsdefend.io <u>Link</u>